<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Paul Cairns</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Paul Cairns</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Paul Cairns</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Belty V2 - The 3D Belt Printer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/belty-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/belty-v2/</guid>
      <description>Equipment Details Belty V2.0 is a belt driven 3D printer designed and built in EnergyLab-Lome. This is the result of our second spiral, which built on our first spiral named Belty. You can find details on how Belty was made here. In the first version we were focused on the belt system and optimising it using the available materials we could lay our hands on. With this Version 2, we focused more on making an actual 3D belt printer where we added an extruder and a new RAMPS control board using the Merlin firmware.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rotary Casting Machine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/rotary-casting-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/rotary-casting-machine/</guid>
      <description>The assignment to be completed over two weeks was to build a machine that had a mechanical and electronic component that could be actuated and automated to perform a certain task. This week I worked with my lab instructor Jason to build a rotary casting and photogrammetry machine. The assignment details and learning outcomes are given below.&#xA;Mechanical Design (part 1 of 2)&#xA;Group assignment:&#xA;Design a machine that includes mechanism + actuation + automation Build the mechanical parts and operate it manually.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The EnergyStove</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/electric-stove/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/electric-stove/</guid>
      <description>Revisions to final video based on comments from final presentation After presenting my final project in the final presentation session, I received the feedback that the final project was good but the video needed the following elements to be demonstrated more clearly:&#xA;Show the functionality of the temperature gauge more clearly Show voltage and current of the pelletier modules to make clear that there is power being generated by them Make it more clear that the fan is working.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
