<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paul Cairns&#39; home page on Paul Cairns</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paul Cairns&#39; home page on Paul Cairns</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Paul Cairns</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>6 Degree of Freedom Robot Arm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electro-mechanics/6-dof-robot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electro-mechanics/6-dof-robot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;background-information&#34;&gt;Background information&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The objective of this project was to learn how to program a 6 DOF robot arm to be used as a pick and place (PnP) machine using computer vision. To do this, I used an off the shelf 6DOF robotic arm that I bought on Amazon called, &amp;ldquo;LeArm&amp;rdquo;. I started by assembling and learning the hardware/mechanics. Next, I had to learn some background information about how to kinematicly define and program the robot arm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A TEDx Talk - Digital Fabrication</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/01-tedx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/01-tedx/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arduino IDE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/programming/arduino-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/programming/arduino-ide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On this page, the objective was to showcase how to program a microcontroller chip on a circuit board that was designed during my &lt;a href=&#34;https://fabacademy.org/2021/labs/vancouver/students/paul-cairns/assignments/9-embedded-programming/&#34;&gt;Fab Academy week 7 &amp;ldquo;electronics design&amp;rdquo; assignment&lt;/a&gt;. As usual, the assignment had a group and individual element. Below are the details.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Compare the performance and development workflows for different microcontroller families&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Document your work (in a group or individually)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Read the datasheet for the microcontroller you are programming&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Program the board you have made to do something, with as many different programming languages and programming environments as possible.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning outcomes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belty V2 - The 3D Belt Printer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/belty-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/belty-v2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;equipment-details&#34;&gt;Equipment Details&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Belty V2.0 is a belt driven 3D printer designed and built in EnergyLab-Lome. This is the result of our second spiral, which built on our first spiral named &lt;a href=&#34;http://fabacademy.org/2023/labs/energylab/machines/belty/&#34;&gt;Belty&lt;/a&gt;. You can find details on how Belty was made &lt;a href=&#34;http://fabacademy.org/2023/labs/energylab/group-assignments/machine-design/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. In the first version we were focused on the belt system and optimising it using the available materials we could lay our hands on. With this Version 2, we focused more on making an actual 3D belt printer where we added an extruder and a new RAMPS control board using the Merlin firmware. Belry V2.0&amp;rsquo;s specifications are included below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer Controlled (CNC) Machining</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/computer-controlled-machining/shop-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/computer-controlled-machining/shop-bot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For this week&amp;rsquo;s assignment, we were tasked with designing, milling, and constructing a large object using a large format CNC machine. The purpose of the assignment was to learn how to use large format CNC machines and how to design for it. As usual, there was a group assignment related to characterising the CNC machine, and an individual assignment, which involved designing and constructing your own piece. Details regarding the requirements of the assignments as well as the learning outcomes are given below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daytime Ottawa - Green Energy Doors Open</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/gedo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/gedo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daytime Ottawa - Old Home Earth Day Event</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/ohede/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/ohede/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Documentary - Canada 150: Aboriginal Insights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/150-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/150-ways/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronics Design: KiCAD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/electronics-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/electronics-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this weeks assignment, we were tasked with designing, milling, soldering, and testing our own circuit board. The purpose of the assignment is to familiarize ourselves with the desgin tools and software (such as KiCad) and also how to test and debug a board. The details of the assignment are below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use the test equipment in your lab to observe the operation of a microcontroller circuit board (in minimum, check operating voltage on the board with multimeter or voltmeter and use oscilloscope to check noise of operating voltage and interpret a data signal)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Document your work (in a group or individually)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronics production</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/electronics-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/electronics-production/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The assignment for this week was to learn the basics of electronics production by milling PCB board with a benchtop CNC machine, and soldering the components to it. This week there were group and individual assignments. The assignments were:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Group assignment&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Characterize the design rules for your PCB production process: document feeds,  speeds, plunge rate, depth of cut (traces and outline) and tooling.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;document your work (in a group or individually)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Individual assignment&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy &amp; Fuels - High Pressure DCSG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/hiprox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/hiprox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Citation: High-Pressure Oxy-Firing (HiPrOx) of Fuels with Water for the Purpose of Direct Contact Steam Generation&#xA;Paul E. C. Cairns, Bruce R. Clements, Robin Hughes, Ted Herage, Ligang Zheng, Arturo Macchi, and Edward J. Anthony&#xA;Energy &amp;amp; Fuels 2015 29 (7), 4522-4533&#xA;DOI: 10.1021/ef502754h&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;High-pressure oxy-fired direct contact steam generation (HiPrOx/DCSG) can be achieved by the oxy-combustion of fuels in the presence of water. This process is capable of producing flue gas streams containing approximately 90% steam with a balance of primarily CO2. The product flue gas is suitable for processes where the purity of the steam is less important, such as the steam-assisted gravity drainage process used for in situ production of bitumen within the Canadian oil sands. This study had three primary objectives: (1) To show that high-moisture HiPrOx/DCSG can be achieved with hydrocarbon fuels. For this purpose, n-butanol was used because of its high volatility and ease of handling. (2) To see if this technology could be applied to fuels with lower volatilities. This was studied by attempting to combust a graphite–water slurry as well as mixtures of graphite–water slurry and butanol. (3) To determine the effects of different fuel mixtures, oxygen-to-fuel ratios, and water inputs on process stability and H2O partial pressure in the product gas. This paper describes pilot-scale combustion testing and process modeling of n-butanol, graphite–water slurry, and their mixtures in an atmosphere consisting of oxygen and water at a pressure of 1.5 MPa(g). Graphite/butanol mixtures were selected because certain combinations could represent the range of fixed carbon/volatiles ratios of waste fuels and indicate whether low-volatile fuels will ignite in the high-water moderator environment. Over the butanol test periods, a steam content of around 90 mol % at saturation was achievable; the O2 in the combustion products was between 0.08 and 3.57 mol % (wet) with an average of 1.13 mol % (wet). The CO emissions were low (&amp;lt;25 ppmv wet, 3% O2) in the combustor. The CO levels indicated that high fuel conversion was achieved with low excess O2 content in the combustion products. The testing also indicated that operation with extremely low O2 is possible for specific fuels, which will minimize downstream corrosion issues and reduce the energy consumption and costs associated with oxygen production requirements. Low CO emissions (&amp;lt;25 ppmv wet, 3% O2) and relatively good process stability were experienced for the butanol/graphite–water slurry mixtures containing ∼40% butanol. CO emissions increased and process stability decreased as the graphite content in the fuel mixture was increased. Unassisted combustion of the graphite–water slurry was achieved for a period of 20 minutes until operational problems were encountered, due to burner plugging by the slurry, requiring that the burner be shut off. It was found that the maximum attainable H2O content in the product gas increased with increasing hydrogen-to-carbon ratio in the fuel. H2O content was around 80 mol % with 100% graphite–water slurry, 81 mol % with a 25% butanol in graphite–water slurry mixture, and around 86.5% in a 40% butanol in graphite–water slurry mixture. It was also found that the fuel H/C ratio, excess O2, heat loss, O2 purity, and fuel volatility are important parameters when considering a DCSG system because they directly affect the process performance and quality of the desired product.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Face Follower - An AI and hardware fusion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/face-follower/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/face-follower/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class = &#34;card py-4&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;video controls autoplay loop muted class =&#34;embed-responsive-item&#34;&gt; &#xA;     &lt;source&#xA;        src=&#34;demo.mp4&#34; &#xA;        type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/video&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;background-and-inspiration&#34;&gt;Background and Inspiration&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I came across this video on social media and got inspired to see if I could replicate it by dusting off an old face detection app I made that uses OpenCV.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The video of the project that inspired this is below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;iframe style=&#34;position: absolute; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34;&#xA;        src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/f2TUxoaKIsA&#34; &#xA;        allowfullscreen &#xA;        frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&#xA;        class = &#34;pt-3 pb-5&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As part of the challenge, I wanted to avoid looking at any documentation that the project included and just try to design the project from scratch using only the video as guidance and to see how I might be able to improve upon the hardware.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FDM - 3D Printing and Scanning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/3d-printing/fdm-printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/3d-printing/fdm-printing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img class=&#34;img-fluid pt-4 pb-5&#34;&#xA;     src=&#34;thumbnail.jpg&#34;&#xA;     alt=&#34;thumbnail.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;assignment-overview&#34;&gt;Assignment Overview&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The assignment for this week was to learn how to characterise and use 3D printers, learn how to 3D scan an object, and  to design a part that can not be easily made subtractively and print it using a 3d printer. As with most weeks, there were group assignments and individual assignments. The details of which are listed below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Test the design rules for your printer(s)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Document your work and explain what are the limits of   your printer(s) (in a group or individually)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FreeCAD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/computer-aided-design/freecad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/computer-aided-design/freecad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I worked on defining my final project idea and started to get used to the documentation process. The learning objectives for the assignment this week are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a. Evaluate and select 2D and 3D software&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b. Demonstrate and describe processes used in modelling with 2D and 3D software&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;c. Model experimental objects/part of a possible project in 2D and 3D software&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;d. Show how I did it with words/images/screenshots&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geppeto the benchtop CNC</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/geppeto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/geppeto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Geppeto was the first in-house machine that I built at EnergyLab Lome. It is a 3-axis CNC machine with a frame made of 3D printed parts, combined with off the shelf rods and lead screws. The motors are 1.5 A nema 17, and it is all controlled using an arduino with CNC shield and grbl controller.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was a great project, that took a while to master and many contributors. I would like to personally thank Hadnane OURO-AGBE, Matt STEDMAN, and Edward YAKUBU, for their contributions to the project over time and for helping bring it to life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GUI Programming with Processing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/programming/graphic-user-interface/processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/programming/graphic-user-interface/processing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Compare as many tool options as possible.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual Assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Write an application that interfaces a user with an input and/or output device that you made&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Outcomes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Interpret and implement design and programming protocols to create a Graphic User Interface (GUI).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Document your process&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Explain the UI that you made and how you did it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Outline problems and how you fixed them&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Include original code (or a screenshot of the app code if that&amp;rsquo;s not possible)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Included a ‘hero shot/video’ of your application running with your board&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;group-assignment&#34;&gt;Group Assignment&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the group assingment we looked at various interfaces such as:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Pressure Oxy-fired Combustion Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/dcsg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/dcsg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;page-still-under-construction&#34;&gt;PAGE STILL UNDER CONSTRUCTION!&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-background-information&#34;&gt;1. Background Information&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A more detailed video about the project is included below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;iframe style=&#34;position: absolute; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34;&#xA;        src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/mannAO6f70c&#34; &#xA;        allowfullscreen &#xA;        frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&#xA;        class = &#34;pt-3 pb-5&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;aspects-of-the-project&#34;&gt;Aspects of the project&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project was very much a 6 year entire research program, as such there were very many aspects of it that I was involved with. Below is list of them. I will cover each in detail in Section 2.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Input devices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/embedded-programming/input-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/embedded-programming/input-devices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The objective for this week was to learn about input devices. For my final project, I will need to measure and output the current, voltage, and temperature. Therefore, I elected to learn to use and program these input devices for this week. The assignment overview and learning outcomes are shared below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Probe an input device(s)&amp;rsquo;s analog and digital signals&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Document your work (in a group or individually)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IPCC - Char Reactivity in Different Environments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/ipcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/ipcc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Citation: Cairns, Paul &amp;amp; Clements, Bruce &amp;amp; Anthony, Edward &amp;amp; Macchi, A.. (2011). Combustion of solid fuels in high pressure oxygen environments under different firing scenarios. 28th Annual International Pittsburgh Coal Conference 2011, PCC 2011. 2. 963-977.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oxy-fired combustion has been identified as one of the promising technologies for CO2 capture because it is capable of producing a concentrated CO2 stream suitable for sequestration. The use of pressurized oxy-fired combustion leads to certain advantages including thermal efficiency gains and physical size reduction of the combustor and flue gas treatment equipment. High pressure oxy-fired (HiPrOx) combustion systems have been proposed for use in power generation applications which fire coal with either a wet or dry flue gas recycle stream as a method for temperature moderation. HiPrOx has also been proposed for direct contact steam generation (DCSG) for use in industrial applications such as heavy oil extraction with solid fuels such as petroleum coke or asphaltenes. These firing scenarios present unique operating conditions and chemical species concentrations that affect the combustion characteristics of solid fuel chars. TGA experiments were performed to study the effects of steam on a Canadian high-volatile bituminous coal char&amp;rsquo;s reactivity in an oxy-fuel (O2/CO2/H 2O) environment. It was found that under kinetically controlled conditions, the increased addition of steam led to a reduction in burning time and temperature. The findings may have resulted from the lower heat capacity and higher thermal conductivity of steam compared to CO2. These results differed from the lower gas temperatures observed near the burner of a pilot scale plant using a wet primary gas recycle in another study. It was postulated that, the suppression of H radical concentrations resulting from the presence of H2O and CO2 during homogeneous ignition may have a greater affect on combustion temperature than the higher thermal conductivity and lower heat capacity of H2O present in the environments investigated in this study.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. Composite Science - Composite Pavement Blocks from Waste LDBE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/pavers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/pavers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Citation: Tsala-Mbala, C.; Hayibo, K.S.; Meyer, T.K.; Couao-Zotti, N.; Cairns, P.; Pearce, J.M. Technical and Economic Viability of Distributed Recycling of Low-Density Polyethylene Water Sachets into Waste Composite Pavement Blocks. J. Compos. Sci. 2022, 6, 289. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/jcs6100289&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/jcs6100289&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In many developing countries, plastic waste management is left to citizens. This usually results in landfilling or hazardous open-air burning, leading to emissions that are harmful to human health and the environment. An easy, profitable, and clean method of processing and transforming the waste into value is required. In this context, this study provides an open-source methodology to transform low-density polyethylene drinking water sachets, into pavement blocks by using a streamlined do-it-yourself approach that requires only modest capital. Two different materials, sand, and ashes are evaluated as additives in plastic composites and the mechanical strength of the resulting blocks are tested for different proportion mix of plastic, sand, and ash. The best composite had an elastic modulus of 169 MPa, a compressive strength of 29 MPa, and a water absorptivity of 2.2%. The composite pavers can be sold at 100% profit while employing workers at 1.5× the minimum wage. In the West African region, this technology has the potential to produce 19 million pavement tiles from 28,000 tons of plastic water sachets annually in Ghana, Nigeria, and Liberia. This can contribute to waste management in the region while generating a gross revenue of 2.85 billion XOF (4.33 million USD).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laser Cutting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/laser-cutting/trotec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/laser-cutting/trotec/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The assignment for this week was to learn the basics of computer controlled cutting using a vinyl cutter and a laser cutter. The assignments for this week were:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Group assignment&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;characterize your lasercutter&amp;rsquo;s focus, power, speed, rate, kerf, and joint clearance&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;document your work (individually or in group)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Individual assignments&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Design, lasercut, and document a parametric press-fit construction kit, which can be assembled in multiple ways. Account for the lasercutter kerf.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;cut something on the vinylcutter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The desired learning outcomes for the week were to:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Master&#39;s Thesis - Chemical Engineering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/masters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Presentation of my final thesis for completion of my Master&amp;rsquo;s Degree in chemical engineering. The work comprised of 5 papers that were submitted for publication discussing the topic of High Pressure Oxy-fired Direct Contact Steam Generation for Steam Assisted Gravity Application.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Production in Canada’s oil sands has been increasing, with a projected rate of 4.5 million barrels per day by 2025. Two production techniques are currently used, mining and in-situ, with the latter projected to constitute ~57% of all production by that time. Although in-situ extraction methods such as Steam Assisted Gravity Drainage (SAGD) are less invasive than mining, they result in more greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions per barrel and require large amounts of water that must be treated and recycled with a make-up water requirement of about 10%. CanmetENERGY is developing a steam generation technology called the High Pressure Oxy-fired Direct Contact Steam Generator (HiPrOx/DCSG, or DCSG for short) that will reduce these water requirements and sequester GHGs. This study evaluates the technical feasibility of this technology using process simulations, bench-scale testing, and pilot-scale testing. At first, a method in which to integrate the DCSG into the SAGD process was presented and process modeling of expected system performance was undertaken. The process simulations indicated that DCSG decreased the energy intensity of SAGD by up to 7.6% compared to the base SAGD case without carbon capture and storage (CCS), and up to 12.0% compared to the base SAGD case with CCS. Bench-scale testing was then performed using a pressurized thermogravimetric analyzer (PTGA) in order to investigate the effects of increased pressure and high moisture environments on a Canadian lignite coal char’s reactivity. It was found that under reaction kinetic-controlled conditions at atmospheric pressure, the increased addition of steam led to a reduction in burning time. The findings may have resulted from the lower heat capacity and higher thermal conductivity of steam compared to CO2. At increased pressures, CO2 inhibited burnout due to its higher heat capacity, lower thermal conductivity, and its effect on C(O) concentrations on the particle surface. When steam was added, the inhibiting effects of CO2 were counteracted, resulting in burnout rates similar to pressurized O2/N2 environments. These preliminary results suggested that the technology was feasible at a bench-scale level. Conflicting literature between bench-scale and pilot-scale studies indicated that pilot-scale testing would be advantageous as a next step. At the pilot-scale, testing was performed using n-butanol, graphite slurry, and n-butanol/graphite slurry mixtures covering lower and upper ends in fuel reactivity. It was found that stable combustion was attainable, with high conversion efficiencies in all cases. With the n-butanol, it was possible to achieve low excess oxygen requirements, which minimizes corrosion issues and reduce energy requirements associated with oxygen generation. With graphite slurry, it was found that it was possible to sustain combustion in these high moisture environments and that high conversion was achieved as indicated by the undetectable levels of carbonaceous materials observed in downstream equipment. Overall, these studies indicate that DCSG is technically feasible from the perspectives of energy and combustion efficiencies as well as from a steam generation point of view. Future work includes the investigation of possible corrosion associated with the product gas, the effect of CO2 on bitumen production, the nature of the mineral melt formed by the deposition of the dissolved and suspended solids from the water in the combustor, and possible scaling issues in the steam generator and piping associated with mineral deposits from the dissolved and&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIT AppInventor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/programming/graphic-user-interface/mit-app-inventor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/programming/graphic-user-interface/mit-app-inventor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The objective of this exercise was to control a drone that we programmed on an ESP32 using a cell phone app connected over bluetooth. You can see a demonstration in the video below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class = &#34;card py-4&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;video controls autoplay loop muted class =&#34;embed-responsive-item&#34;&gt; &#xA;     &lt;source&#xA;        src=&#34;appDemo.mp4&#34; &#xA;        type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/video&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-it-worked&#34;&gt;How it worked&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you can see in the video, we were controlling the four motors of a drone. We wrote an auto levelling program that would read the roll, pitch, and yaw from a gyroscope and determine the drone&amp;rsquo;s orientation. Depending on its orientation different motors would be sent power. There are more details specific to the auto-levelling program on the drone project page (LINK COMING).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molding and casting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/molding-and-casting/rotary-casting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/molding-and-casting/rotary-casting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The assignment for this week was to desisgn and cast a omponent by 3D milling a piece and making a mold to cast with. For my final project, the Thermoelectric Generation (TEG) and electronics cover is too large to print using the 3D printer, therefore I have elected to rotary cast it this week. As usual there is both a group assignment and an individual assignment. Details regarding the assignments for this week are given below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Networking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/embedded-programming/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/embedded-programming/networking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The assignment for this week was to build a second board and communicate between two boards using some sort of networking protocol. For this assignment I chose to use the I2C networking protocol. Details regarding the requierements for this weeks assignment are below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Send a message between two projects&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Design, build, and connect wired or wireless node(s) with network or bus addresses&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning outcomes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate workflows used in network design&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Implement and interpret networking protocols and/or communication protocols&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Document your project&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Document what you have learned from implementing networking and/or communication protocols.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Explain the programming process/es you used.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Outline problems and how you fixed them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Include design files (or linked to where they are located if you are using a board you have designed and fabricated earlier) and original code.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;group-assignment&#34;&gt;Group Assignment&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I am the only student at my lab for the group assignment I simply sent a message between the two boards that will be used for my project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OnShape</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/computer-aided-design/onshape/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/computer-aided-design/onshape/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project I will work on using OnShape is a omnidirectional gear that I plan to 3D print using my SLA printer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-onshape&#34;&gt;About OnShape&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;OnShape is an online 3D modelling software that is ideal for collaborating on a project. It is not the most rigorous CAD tool, but there is a free version and it is quite user intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;row justify-content-center&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img class=&#34;img-fluid py-4&#34;&#xA;     src=&#34;home.png&#34;&#xA;     alt=&#34;home.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it has several usefull libraries such as the Beam add-on for quickly creating 8020 extrusions. Its online and open model has enabled a lot of interesting development and add-ons such as this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Output Devices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/embedded-programming/output-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/embedded-programming/output-devices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The assignment for this week was to learn about output devices. For my final project, I will need to measure and output the current, voltage, and temperature onto LED displays and an LED bargraph. Therefore, I elected to learn how to use and program these output devices this week. The assignment overview and learning outcomes are shared below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The tasks for the group assignment are as follows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Measure the power consumption of an output device&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Document your work (in a group or individually)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcast - The Conscious Builder Podcast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/conscious-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/conscious-builder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rotary Casting Machine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/rotary-casting-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/rotary-casting-machine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The assignment to be completed over two weeks was to build a machine that had a mechanical and electronic component that could be actuated and automated to perform a certain task. This week I worked with my lab instructor Jason to build a rotary casting and photogrammetry machine. The assignment details and learning outcomes are given below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mechanical Design (part 1 of 2)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Design a machine that includes mechanism + actuation + automation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Build the mechanical parts and operate it manually.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Document the group project&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individual assignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SLA - 3D Printing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/3d-printing/sla-printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/3d-printing/sla-printing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project I will work on using OnShape is a omnidirectional gear that I plan to 3D print using my SLA printer. Below is a presentation of the workflow to use the Anycubic Photon Mono 2 SLA printer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;setting-up-the-printer&#34;&gt;Setting up the printer&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SLA printers require minimal setup, simply take it out of the box, place the screen protector on and install the build plate and resin bath. You can learn about the setup process by quickly scrolling through the &lt;a href=&#34;../anycubic-printer.pdf&#34;&gt;User Manual&lt;/a&gt; below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solidworks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/computer-aided-design/solidworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/computer-aided-design/solidworks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project I will work on using Solidworks is a face-follower hardware that will be 3D printed. It will be connected to an Arduino and face detection python algorithm that will follow the face of a person on camera.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-solidworks&#34;&gt;About Solidworks&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Solidworks is a 3D modelling software that is ideal for working on high level high quality engineering projects where advanced assemblies and simulations will be required. It is a hihgly rigorous CAD tool with lots of options for engineering, but it is not free and has a bit of a steeper user learning curve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEES Framework of Capacity Building - Report to EU</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/reports/tees-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/reports/tees-framework/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ENERGICA project is a multifaceted consortium funded by the Horizon 2020 initiative of the&#xA;European Commission. The project brings several consortium members together to support three&#xA;Energy Access demonstration projects across Sub Saharan Africa (SSA). The overall concept of the&#xA;project is “to develop and demonstrate in real environments that existing technologies can be tailored&#xA;through efficient and sustainable community-based approaches in any type of societal contexts”. [1]&#xA;As such, three different contexts for energy access were selected across SSA as demonstrators. They&#xA;are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Mopping</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/blog/mopping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/blog/mopping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-art-of-mopping&#34;&gt;The Art of Mopping&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You missed a spot!&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re doing it too quickly, be smoother, like a dance&amp;hellip; focus Paul&amp;hellip; focus!&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re moving too jerky, smoother&amp;rdquo;, he interrupted my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The words hit me like a ton of bricks, having not heard anyone speak directly to me in so long.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m going quickly because i just want to finish this job and get the hell out of here&amp;rdquo;, I thought, but didn&amp;rsquo;t verbalize.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Digital Fabrication Masterplan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/blog/digital-fabrication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/blog/digital-fabrication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-power-of-digital-fabrication---unleashing-a-new-approach-to-how-we-create-products&#34;&gt;The Power of Digital Fabrication - unleashing a new approach to how we create products&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s 7:43 AM, your alarm went off for the fourth time and you’re late! You jump out of bed, get dressed and run out the door. On the way there, you notice your pants are falling. You forgot your belt! So you make a mad dash back to grab it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let’s stop for a second, and think of the journey that belt took to get to your closet. The journey began in Brazil, then to Bangladesh, to Europe, China, and finally from China to the place you bought it. A total of about 42,000 km! We call this number supply chain mileage. The number of miles a product takes from where the raw materials are harvested to the shelf in a store. Some products have a supply chain mileage of up to 80,000 km! That’s twice the circumference of the earth! Very unsustainable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The EnergyStove</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/electric-stove/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/electric-stove/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class = &#34;card py-4&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;video controls autoplay loop muted class =&#34;embed-responsive-item&#34;&gt; &#xA;     &lt;source&#xA;        src=&#34;presentation.mp4&#34; &#xA;        type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/video&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;revisions-to-final-video-based-on-comments-from-final-presentation&#34;&gt;Revisions to final video based on comments from final presentation&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After presenting my final project in the final presentation session, I received the feedback that the final project was good but the video needed the following elements to be demonstrated more clearly:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Show the functionality of the temperature gauge more clearly&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Show voltage and current of the pelletier modules to make clear that there is power being generated by them&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make it more clear that the fan is working.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Taking these comments into consideration, I performed another more controlled experiment that could better demonstrate the pelletier voltage and current and replaced the section at time 1:05 - 1:12&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turnbull Private School - 150 Ways to Reduce your Carbon Footprint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/turnbull/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/turnbull/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video - Green Energy Doors Open 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/gedo-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/gedo-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video - Green Energy Doors Open 2018</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/gedo-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/gedo-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Documentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/web-development/project-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/web-development/project-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page is based on the first weeks&amp;rsquo; of the FabAcademy. You can visit my Fab Academy page [here] (&lt;a href=&#34;https://fabacademy.org/2021/labs/vancouver/students/paul-cairns/assignments/2-project-management/)&#34;&gt;https://fabacademy.org/2021/labs/vancouver/students/paul-cairns/assignments/2-project-management/)&lt;/a&gt;. The tasks for this assignment included:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Build a personal site describing you and your final project.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Upload it to the class archive.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work through a git tutorial.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We will be evaluated on whether we:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Made a website and described how we did it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Introduced ourself&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Documented the steps for uploading files to archive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pushed to the class archive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The project management aspect of the assignment revolved around 3 key aspects and skills:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/blog/technical-jargon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/blog/technical-jargon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul Cairns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/about/paul-cairns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/about/paul-cairns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello, My name is Paul Cairns, I have a Bachelor’s in Mechanical Engineering, and a Master’s in Chemical Engineering. After graduating I spent six years of my professional career as a Research Engineer for the Government of Canada. I also spent two years as Executive Director for a green energy business incubator based out of Ottawa, Canada. Just over a year ago I joined Energy Generation where I manage the EnergyTech Department and EnergyLab, our FabLab based out of Lomé, Togo. More about that below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
