<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paul Cairns&#39; home page on Paul Cairns</title>
    <link>http://paulcair.github.io/paulcairns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paul Cairns&#39; home page on Paul Cairns</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Paul Cairns</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://paulcair.github.io/paulcairns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> Final Project</title>
      <link>http://paulcair.github.io/paulcairns/projects/electric-stove/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://paulcair.github.io/paulcairns/projects/electric-stove/</guid>
      <description>Revisions to final video based on comments from final presentation After presenting my final project in the final presentation session, I received the feedback that the final project was good but the video needed the following elements to be demonstrated more clearly:&#xA;Show the functionality of the temperature gauge more clearly Show voltage and current of the pelletier modules to make clear that there is power being generated by them Make it more clear that the fan is working.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>01 - Principles and Practices</title>
      <link>http://paulcair.github.io/paulcairns/assignments/1-practice-and-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://paulcair.github.io/paulcairns/assignments/1-practice-and-principles/</guid>
      <description>The assignment for the first week of the FabAcademy is based on the assessments for (Principles and Practices). The tasks for this assignment include:&#xA;Plan and sketch a potential final project Build a personal site describing you and your final project. We will be evaluated on whether we:&#xA;Read the Fab Charter Sketched your final project idea/s Described what it will do and who will use it Signed and uploaded the Student Agreement Final Project Assessment Criteria Before beginning, it is important to understand what is expected of a final project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 - Project Management</title>
      <link>http://paulcair.github.io/paulcairns/assignments/2-project-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://paulcair.github.io/paulcairns/assignments/2-project-management/</guid>
      <description>The assignment for the first week of the FabAcademy is based on the assessments for (Project Management). The tasks for this assignment include:&#xA;Build a personal site describing you and your final project. Upload it to the class archive. Work through a git tutorial. We will be evaluated on whether we:&#xA;Made a website and described how we did it Introduced ourself Documented the steps for uploading files to archive Pushed to the class archive The project management aspect of the assignment revolved around 3 key aspects and skills:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belty V2 - The 3D Belt Printer</title>
      <link>http://paulcair.github.io/paulcairns/projects/belty-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://paulcair.github.io/paulcairns/projects/belty-v2/</guid>
      <description>Equipment Details Belty V2.0 is a belt driven 3D printer designed and built in EnergyLab-Lome. This is the result of our second spiral, which built on our first spiral named Belty. You can find details on how Belty was made here. In the first version we were focused on the belt system and optimising it using the available materials we could lay our hands on. With this Version 2, we focused more on making an actual 3D belt printer where we added an extruder and a new RAMPS control board using the Merlin firmware.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul Cairns</title>
      <link>http://paulcair.github.io/paulcairns/about/paul-cairns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://paulcair.github.io/paulcairns/about/paul-cairns/</guid>
      <description>Hello, My name is Paul Cairns, I have a Bachelor’s in Mechanical Engineering, and a Master’s in Chemical Engineering. After graduating I spent six years of my professional career as a Research Engineer for the Government of Canada. I also spent two years as Executive Director for a green energy business incubator based out of Ottawa, Canada. Just over a year ago I joined Energy Generation where I manage the EnergyTech Department and EnergyLab, our FabLab based out of Lomé, Togo.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
