<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paul Cairns&#39; home page on Paul Cairns</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paul Cairns&#39; home page on Paul Cairns</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Paul Cairns</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>3D Printing and Scanning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/3d-printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/3d-printing/</guid>
      <description>Assignment Overview The assignment for this week was to learn how to characterise and use 3D printers, learn how to 3D scan an object, and to design a part that can not be easily made subtractively and print it using a 3d printer. As with most weeks, there were group assignments and individual assignments. The details of which are listed below.&#xA;Group assignment:&#xA;Test the design rules for your printer(s) Document your work and explain what are the limits of your printer(s) (in a group or individually) Individual assignment:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arduino IDE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/programming/arduino-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/programming/arduino-ide/</guid>
      <description>On this page, the objective was to showcase how to program a microcontroller chip on a circuit board that was designed during my Fab Academy week 7 &amp;ldquo;electronics design&amp;rdquo; assignment. As usual, the assignment had a group and individual element. Below are the details.&#xA;Group assignment:&#xA;Compare the performance and development workflows for different microcontroller families Document your work (in a group or individually) Individual assignment:&#xA;Read the datasheet for the microcontroller you are programming Program the board you have made to do something, with as many different programming languages and programming environments as possible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Belty V2 - The 3D Belt Printer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/belty-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/belty-v2/</guid>
      <description>Equipment Details Belty V2.0 is a belt driven 3D printer designed and built in EnergyLab-Lome. This is the result of our second spiral, which built on our first spiral named Belty. You can find details on how Belty was made here. In the first version we were focused on the belt system and optimising it using the available materials we could lay our hands on. With this Version 2, we focused more on making an actual 3D belt printer where we added an extruder and a new RAMPS control board using the Merlin firmware.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computer Controlled (CNC) Machining</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/computer-controlled-machining/shop-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/computer-controlled-machining/shop-bot/</guid>
      <description>For this week&amp;rsquo;s assignment, we were tasked with designing, milling, and constructing a large object using a large format CNC machine. The purpose of the assignment was to learn how to use large format CNC machines and how to design for it. As usual, there was a group assignment related to characterising the CNC machine, and an individual assignment, which involved designing and constructing your own piece. Details regarding the requirements of the assignments as well as the learning outcomes are given below.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daytime Ottawa - Green Energy Doors Open</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/gedo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/gedo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daytime Ottawa - Old Home Earth Day Event</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/ohede/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/ohede/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Documentary - Canada 150: Aboriginal Insights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/150-ways/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/150-ways/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronics Design: KiCAD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/electronics-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/electronics-design/</guid>
      <description>For this weeks assignment, we were tasked with designing, milling, soldering, and testing our own circuit board. The purpose of the assignment is to familiarize ourselves with the desgin tools and software (such as KiCad) and also how to test and debug a board. The details of the assignment are below.&#xA;Group assignment:&#xA;Use the test equipment in your lab to observe the operation of a microcontroller circuit board (in minimum, check operating voltage on the board with multimeter or voltmeter and use oscilloscope to check noise of operating voltage and interpret a data signal) Document your work (in a group or individually) Individual assignment:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronics production</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/electronics-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/electronics-production/</guid>
      <description>The assignment for this week was to learn the basics of electronics production by milling PCB board with a benchtop CNC machine, and soldering the components to it. This week there were group and individual assignments. The assignments were:&#xA;Group assignment&#xA;Characterize the design rules for your PCB production process: document feeds, speeds, plunge rate, depth of cut (traces and outline) and tooling. document your work (in a group or individually) Individual assignment</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FreeCAD</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/computer-aided-design/freecad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/computer-aided-design/freecad/</guid>
      <description>This week I worked on defining my final project idea and started to get used to the documentation process. The learning objectives for the assignment this week are:&#xA;a. Evaluate and select 2D and 3D software&#xA;b. Demonstrate and describe processes used in modelling with 2D and 3D software&#xA;c. Model experimental objects/part of a possible project in 2D and 3D software&#xA;d. Show how I did it with words/images/screenshots</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GUI Programming with Processing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/programming/graphic-user-interface/processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/programming/graphic-user-interface/processing/</guid>
      <description>Group Assignment:&#xA;Compare as many tool options as possible. Individual Assignment:&#xA;Write an application that interfaces a user with an input and/or output device that you made Learning Outcomes:&#xA;Interpret and implement design and programming protocols to create a Graphic User Interface (GUI). Document your process Explain the UI that you made and how you did it Outline problems and how you fixed them Include original code (or a screenshot of the app code if that&amp;rsquo;s not possible) Included a ‘hero shot/video’ of your application running with your board Group Assignment For the group assingment we looked at various interfaces such as:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Input devices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/embedded-programming/input-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/embedded-programming/input-devices/</guid>
      <description>The objective for this week was to learn about input devices. For my final project, I will need to measure and output the current, voltage, and temperature. Therefore, I elected to learn to use and program these input devices for this week. The assignment overview and learning outcomes are shared below.&#xA;Group assignment:&#xA;Probe an input device(s)&amp;rsquo;s analog and digital signals Document your work (in a group or individually) Individual assignment:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IPCC - Char Reactivity in Different Environments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/ipcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/ipcc/</guid>
      <description>Citation: Cairns, Paul &amp;amp; Clements, Bruce &amp;amp; Anthony, Edward &amp;amp; Macchi, A.. (2011). Combustion of solid fuels in high pressure oxygen environments under different firing scenarios. 28th Annual International Pittsburgh Coal Conference 2011, PCC 2011. 2. 963-977.&#xA;Abstract Oxy-fired combustion has been identified as one of the promising technologies for CO2 capture because it is capable of producing a concentrated CO2 stream suitable for sequestration. The use of pressurized oxy-fired combustion leads to certain advantages including thermal efficiency gains and physical size reduction of the combustor and flue gas treatment equipment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laser Cutting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/laser-cutting/trotec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/laser-cutting/trotec/</guid>
      <description>The assignment for this week was to learn the basics of computer controlled cutting using a vinyl cutter and a laser cutter. The assignments for this week were:&#xA;Group assignment&#xA;characterize your lasercutter&amp;rsquo;s focus, power, speed, rate, kerf, and joint clearance document your work (individually or in group) Individual assignments&#xA;Design, lasercut, and document a parametric press-fit construction kit, which can be assembled in multiple ways. Account for the lasercutter kerf.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Master&#39;s Thesis - Chemical Engineering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/masters/</guid>
      <description>Presentation of my final thesis for completion of my Master&amp;rsquo;s Degree in chemical engineering. The work comprised of 5 papers that were submitted for publication discussing the topic of High Pressure Oxy-fired Direct Contact Steam Generation for Steam Assisted Gravity Application.&#xA;Abstract Production in Canada’s oil sands has been increasing, with a projected rate of 4.5 million barrels per day by 2025. Two production techniques are currently used, mining and in-situ, with the latter projected to constitute ~57% of all production by that time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIT AppInventor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/programming/graphic-user-interface/mit-app-inventor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/programming/graphic-user-interface/mit-app-inventor/</guid>
      <description>Overview The objective of this exercise was to control a drone that we programmed on an ESP32 using a cell phone app connected over bluetooth. You can see a demonstration in the video below:&#xA;How it worked As you can see in the video, we were controlling the four motors of a drone. We wrote an auto levelling program that would read the roll, pitch, and yaw from a gyroscope and determine the drone&amp;rsquo;s orientation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molding and casting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/molding-and-casting/rotary-casting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/molding-and-casting/rotary-casting/</guid>
      <description>The assignment for this week was to desisgn and cast a omponent by 3D milling a piece and making a mold to cast with. For my final project, the Thermoelectric Generation (TEG) and electronics cover is too large to print using the 3D printer, therefore I have elected to rotary cast it this week. As usual there is both a group assignment and an individual assignment. Details regarding the assignments for this week are given below.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Networking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/embedded-programming/networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/embedded-programming/networking/</guid>
      <description>The assignment for this week was to build a second board and communicate between two boards using some sort of networking protocol. For this assignment I chose to use the I2C networking protocol. Details regarding the requierements for this weeks assignment are below.&#xA;Group assignment:&#xA;Send a message between two projects Individual assignment:&#xA;Design, build, and connect wired or wireless node(s) with network or bus addresses Learning outcomes:&#xA;Demonstrate workflows used in network design Implement and interpret networking protocols and/or communication protocols Document your project Document what you have learned from implementing networking and/or communication protocols.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Output Devices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/embedded-programming/output-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/electronics/embedded-programming/output-devices/</guid>
      <description>The assignment for this week was to learn about output devices. For my final project, I will need to measure and output the current, voltage, and temperature onto LED displays and an LED bargraph. Therefore, I elected to learn how to use and program these output devices this week. The assignment overview and learning outcomes are shared below.&#xA;Group assignment:&#xA;The tasks for the group assignment are as follows.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcast - The Conscious Builder Podcast</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/conscious-builder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/conscious-builder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rotary Casting Machine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/rotary-casting-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/rotary-casting-machine/</guid>
      <description>The assignment to be completed over two weeks was to build a machine that had a mechanical and electronic component that could be actuated and automated to perform a certain task. This week I worked with my lab instructor Jason to build a rotary casting and photogrammetry machine. The assignment details and learning outcomes are given below.&#xA;Mechanical Design (part 1 of 2)&#xA;Group assignment:&#xA;Design a machine that includes mechanism + actuation + automation Build the mechanical parts and operate it manually.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TEES Framework of Capacity Building - Report to EU</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/reports/tees-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/reports/tees-framework/</guid>
      <description>Background The ENERGICA project is a multifaceted consortium funded by the Horizon 2020 initiative of the European Commission. The project brings several consortium members together to support three Energy Access demonstration projects across Sub Saharan Africa (SSA). The overall concept of the project is “to develop and demonstrate in real environments that existing technologies can be tailored through efficient and sustainable community-based approaches in any type of societal contexts”. [1] As such, three different contexts for energy access were selected across SSA as demonstrators.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The EnergyStove</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/electric-stove/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/projects/electric-stove/</guid>
      <description>Revisions to final video based on comments from final presentation After presenting my final project in the final presentation session, I received the feedback that the final project was good but the video needed the following elements to be demonstrated more clearly:&#xA;Show the functionality of the temperature gauge more clearly Show voltage and current of the pelletier modules to make clear that there is power being generated by them Make it more clear that the fan is working.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turnbull Private School - 150 Ways to Reduce your Carbon Footprint</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/turnbull/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/turnbull/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video - Green Energy Doors Open 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/gedo-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/gedo-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video - Green Energy Doors Open 2018</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/gedo-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/videos/gedo-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web Documentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/web-development/project-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/skillsportfolio/web-development/project-documentation/</guid>
      <description>This page is based on the first weeks&amp;rsquo; of the FabAcademy. You can visit my Fab Academy page [here] (https://fabacademy.org/2021/labs/vancouver/students/paul-cairns/assignments/2-project-management/). The tasks for this assignment included:&#xA;Build a personal site describing you and your final project. Upload it to the class archive. Work through a git tutorial. We will be evaluated on whether we:&#xA;Made a website and described how we did it Introduced ourself Documented the steps for uploading files to archive Pushed to the class archive The project management aspect of the assignment revolved around 3 key aspects and skills:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul Cairns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/about/paul-cairns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/about/paul-cairns/</guid>
      <description>Hello, My name is Paul Cairns, I have a Bachelor’s in Mechanical Engineering, and a Master’s in Chemical Engineering. After graduating I spent six years of my professional career as a Research Engineer for the Government of Canada. I also spent two years as Executive Director for a green energy business incubator based out of Ottawa, Canada. Just over a year ago I joined Energy Generation where I manage the EnergyTech Department and EnergyLab, our FabLab based out of Lomé, Togo.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
