<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scientific Papers on Paul Cairns</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Scientific Papers on Paul Cairns</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Paul Cairns</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Energy &amp; Fuels - High Pressure DCSG</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/hiprox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/hiprox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Citation: High-Pressure Oxy-Firing (HiPrOx) of Fuels with Water for the Purpose of Direct Contact Steam Generation&#xA;Paul E. C. Cairns, Bruce R. Clements, Robin Hughes, Ted Herage, Ligang Zheng, Arturo Macchi, and Edward J. Anthony&#xA;Energy &amp;amp; Fuels 2015 29 (7), 4522-4533&#xA;DOI: 10.1021/ef502754h&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;High-pressure oxy-fired direct contact steam generation (HiPrOx/DCSG) can be achieved by the oxy-combustion of fuels in the presence of water. This process is capable of producing flue gas streams containing approximately 90% steam with a balance of primarily CO2. The product flue gas is suitable for processes where the purity of the steam is less important, such as the steam-assisted gravity drainage process used for in situ production of bitumen within the Canadian oil sands. This study had three primary objectives: (1) To show that high-moisture HiPrOx/DCSG can be achieved with hydrocarbon fuels. For this purpose, n-butanol was used because of its high volatility and ease of handling. (2) To see if this technology could be applied to fuels with lower volatilities. This was studied by attempting to combust a graphite–water slurry as well as mixtures of graphite–water slurry and butanol. (3) To determine the effects of different fuel mixtures, oxygen-to-fuel ratios, and water inputs on process stability and H2O partial pressure in the product gas. This paper describes pilot-scale combustion testing and process modeling of n-butanol, graphite–water slurry, and their mixtures in an atmosphere consisting of oxygen and water at a pressure of 1.5 MPa(g). Graphite/butanol mixtures were selected because certain combinations could represent the range of fixed carbon/volatiles ratios of waste fuels and indicate whether low-volatile fuels will ignite in the high-water moderator environment. Over the butanol test periods, a steam content of around 90 mol % at saturation was achievable; the O2 in the combustion products was between 0.08 and 3.57 mol % (wet) with an average of 1.13 mol % (wet). The CO emissions were low (&amp;lt;25 ppmv wet, 3% O2) in the combustor. The CO levels indicated that high fuel conversion was achieved with low excess O2 content in the combustion products. The testing also indicated that operation with extremely low O2 is possible for specific fuels, which will minimize downstream corrosion issues and reduce the energy consumption and costs associated with oxygen production requirements. Low CO emissions (&amp;lt;25 ppmv wet, 3% O2) and relatively good process stability were experienced for the butanol/graphite–water slurry mixtures containing ∼40% butanol. CO emissions increased and process stability decreased as the graphite content in the fuel mixture was increased. Unassisted combustion of the graphite–water slurry was achieved for a period of 20 minutes until operational problems were encountered, due to burner plugging by the slurry, requiring that the burner be shut off. It was found that the maximum attainable H2O content in the product gas increased with increasing hydrogen-to-carbon ratio in the fuel. H2O content was around 80 mol % with 100% graphite–water slurry, 81 mol % with a 25% butanol in graphite–water slurry mixture, and around 86.5% in a 40% butanol in graphite–water slurry mixture. It was also found that the fuel H/C ratio, excess O2, heat loss, O2 purity, and fuel volatility are important parameters when considering a DCSG system because they directly affect the process performance and quality of the desired product.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IPCC - Char Reactivity in Different Environments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/ipcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/ipcc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Citation: Cairns, Paul &amp;amp; Clements, Bruce &amp;amp; Anthony, Edward &amp;amp; Macchi, A.. (2011). Combustion of solid fuels in high pressure oxygen environments under different firing scenarios. 28th Annual International Pittsburgh Coal Conference 2011, PCC 2011. 2. 963-977.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oxy-fired combustion has been identified as one of the promising technologies for CO2 capture because it is capable of producing a concentrated CO2 stream suitable for sequestration. The use of pressurized oxy-fired combustion leads to certain advantages including thermal efficiency gains and physical size reduction of the combustor and flue gas treatment equipment. High pressure oxy-fired (HiPrOx) combustion systems have been proposed for use in power generation applications which fire coal with either a wet or dry flue gas recycle stream as a method for temperature moderation. HiPrOx has also been proposed for direct contact steam generation (DCSG) for use in industrial applications such as heavy oil extraction with solid fuels such as petroleum coke or asphaltenes. These firing scenarios present unique operating conditions and chemical species concentrations that affect the combustion characteristics of solid fuel chars. TGA experiments were performed to study the effects of steam on a Canadian high-volatile bituminous coal char&amp;rsquo;s reactivity in an oxy-fuel (O2/CO2/H 2O) environment. It was found that under kinetically controlled conditions, the increased addition of steam led to a reduction in burning time and temperature. The findings may have resulted from the lower heat capacity and higher thermal conductivity of steam compared to CO2. These results differed from the lower gas temperatures observed near the burner of a pilot scale plant using a wet primary gas recycle in another study. It was postulated that, the suppression of H radical concentrations resulting from the presence of H2O and CO2 during homogeneous ignition may have a greater affect on combustion temperature than the higher thermal conductivity and lower heat capacity of H2O present in the environments investigated in this study.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>J. Composite Science - Composite Pavement Blocks from Waste LDBE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/pavers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/pavers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Citation: Tsala-Mbala, C.; Hayibo, K.S.; Meyer, T.K.; Couao-Zotti, N.; Cairns, P.; Pearce, J.M. Technical and Economic Viability of Distributed Recycling of Low-Density Polyethylene Water Sachets into Waste Composite Pavement Blocks. J. Compos. Sci. 2022, 6, 289. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3390/jcs6100289&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3390/jcs6100289&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In many developing countries, plastic waste management is left to citizens. This usually results in landfilling or hazardous open-air burning, leading to emissions that are harmful to human health and the environment. An easy, profitable, and clean method of processing and transforming the waste into value is required. In this context, this study provides an open-source methodology to transform low-density polyethylene drinking water sachets, into pavement blocks by using a streamlined do-it-yourself approach that requires only modest capital. Two different materials, sand, and ashes are evaluated as additives in plastic composites and the mechanical strength of the resulting blocks are tested for different proportion mix of plastic, sand, and ash. The best composite had an elastic modulus of 169 MPa, a compressive strength of 29 MPa, and a water absorptivity of 2.2%. The composite pavers can be sold at 100% profit while employing workers at 1.5× the minimum wage. In the West African region, this technology has the potential to produce 19 million pavement tiles from 28,000 tons of plastic water sachets annually in Ghana, Nigeria, and Liberia. This can contribute to waste management in the region while generating a gross revenue of 2.85 billion XOF (4.33 million USD).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Master&#39;s Thesis - Chemical Engineering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/masters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/paulcairns/publications/scientific-papers/masters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Presentation of my final thesis for completion of my Master&amp;rsquo;s Degree in chemical engineering. The work comprised of 5 papers that were submitted for publication discussing the topic of High Pressure Oxy-fired Direct Contact Steam Generation for Steam Assisted Gravity Application.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Production in Canada’s oil sands has been increasing, with a projected rate of 4.5 million barrels per day by 2025. Two production techniques are currently used, mining and in-situ, with the latter projected to constitute ~57% of all production by that time. Although in-situ extraction methods such as Steam Assisted Gravity Drainage (SAGD) are less invasive than mining, they result in more greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions per barrel and require large amounts of water that must be treated and recycled with a make-up water requirement of about 10%. CanmetENERGY is developing a steam generation technology called the High Pressure Oxy-fired Direct Contact Steam Generator (HiPrOx/DCSG, or DCSG for short) that will reduce these water requirements and sequester GHGs. This study evaluates the technical feasibility of this technology using process simulations, bench-scale testing, and pilot-scale testing. At first, a method in which to integrate the DCSG into the SAGD process was presented and process modeling of expected system performance was undertaken. The process simulations indicated that DCSG decreased the energy intensity of SAGD by up to 7.6% compared to the base SAGD case without carbon capture and storage (CCS), and up to 12.0% compared to the base SAGD case with CCS. Bench-scale testing was then performed using a pressurized thermogravimetric analyzer (PTGA) in order to investigate the effects of increased pressure and high moisture environments on a Canadian lignite coal char’s reactivity. It was found that under reaction kinetic-controlled conditions at atmospheric pressure, the increased addition of steam led to a reduction in burning time. The findings may have resulted from the lower heat capacity and higher thermal conductivity of steam compared to CO2. At increased pressures, CO2 inhibited burnout due to its higher heat capacity, lower thermal conductivity, and its effect on C(O) concentrations on the particle surface. When steam was added, the inhibiting effects of CO2 were counteracted, resulting in burnout rates similar to pressurized O2/N2 environments. These preliminary results suggested that the technology was feasible at a bench-scale level. Conflicting literature between bench-scale and pilot-scale studies indicated that pilot-scale testing would be advantageous as a next step. At the pilot-scale, testing was performed using n-butanol, graphite slurry, and n-butanol/graphite slurry mixtures covering lower and upper ends in fuel reactivity. It was found that stable combustion was attainable, with high conversion efficiencies in all cases. With the n-butanol, it was possible to achieve low excess oxygen requirements, which minimizes corrosion issues and reduce energy requirements associated with oxygen generation. With graphite slurry, it was found that it was possible to sustain combustion in these high moisture environments and that high conversion was achieved as indicated by the undetectable levels of carbonaceous materials observed in downstream equipment. Overall, these studies indicate that DCSG is technically feasible from the perspectives of energy and combustion efficiencies as well as from a steam generation point of view. Future work includes the investigation of possible corrosion associated with the product gas, the effect of CO2 on bitumen production, the nature of the mineral melt formed by the deposition of the dissolved and suspended solids from the water in the combustor, and possible scaling issues in the steam generator and piping associated with mineral deposits from the dissolved and&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
